你被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
联系系统管理员
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror
身份不明
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
身份不明
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
政府认为这些人无关紧要
The government considered these people irrelevant.
关键执行人
我们不
We don't.
失踪
关键执行人
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
状态：纽约警局任职
你永远找不到我们
You'll never find us.
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪
第二季 第十集
威胁评估  访问硬盘
会话分析  语言识别
妈  爸
Hi, mom. Hi, dad.
要是你们看到这个  就说明我现在有麻烦了
If you're watching this, you'll know I'm in trouble.
我一直都很乖
I've always tried to be good,
循规蹈矩
keep the rules.
这次我要干件彻底逆转的大事
Now I'm gonna break them in a big way.
人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：阿好  紫玉  zhanginfo  Didina  天朝直属
时间轴：擦擦  GGwhywhy
特效&后期：灰灰是菇凉   校对&总监： 阿好
安抚住他
Just hold him still.
小熊  趴下  坐好
Bear, afliggen! Sit.
可真是帮了大忙了
Well, that was a big help.
你说我们又有新号码了
So, you said we had another number?
是的  艾比・门罗  26岁
Yes. Abby Monroe, 26.
学校里的优秀学生  有工程学学位
Honor student at school, degree in engineering.
去年在一家军人慈善组织工作
She's worked for the last year at a military charity,
名叫"归国英雄之家"
Homes For Our Returning Heroes,
也许是因为她弟弟
Maybe because her younger brother
一年半前在阿富汗牺牲
was killed in Afghanistan 18 months ago.
她上周从那家慈善组织辞职了
She quit the charity a week ago.
现在在城市规划办公室做短期工
She's now working as a temp in a city planning office.
发现威胁了吗
Any threats?
没发现  不过有些异常
Not that I can see, but some anomalies.
她五天前弃用了电话
She dumped her phone five days ago
搬出了公寓
and moved out of her apartment.
其实  我现在追踪她
In fact, the only way I could trace her
只能靠短期工中介
was through the temp agency.
她在躲什么人
She's hiding from someone.
我最好盯紧她
I'd better get eyes on her.
轮到你来吹干了
It's your turn to dry him.
她随时可能有危险啊  芬奇
She could be in imminent danger, Finch.
里瑟先生  这是你的狗
Mr. Reese, he's your dog.
你搞定呗
You'll manage.
-你好警探  -你好警探
- Detective. - Detective.
上次晚餐很好玩  我们再约一次如何
Dinner was fun. What about doing it again?
我今晚刚好有空  真巧
I'm free tonight, as it happens.
抱歉  我有个案子要跟
Sorry. Got a case I'm looking at.
其实就是他  戴维森
Him, actually. Davidson.
失踪
伊恩・戴维森警探
去年冬天失踪的内务部警察
The Internal Affairs cop went missing last winter.
你认识他吗
Did you know him?
岂止认识  我还跟他有过节
Know him? I had some run-ins with him.
有什么发现
What's your interest?
有条线报  匿名的
I got a tip, anonymous.
说他被个警察谋杀了
Said a cop killed him.
也许他牵扯进了HR的生意中
Well, maybe he was mixed up in some HR business.
也许HR的警察把他弄掉了
Maybe an HR cop took him out.
我听说51局之前有人清毒贩
I heard of one group out of the 51st was offing dealers
出他们的货
and selling their supply.
你知道都有谁吗
You got any names?
大部分不是坐牢了就是死掉了  但也不是全部
Most of them are behind bars or dead, but not all of them.
能打扰一下吗
Will you excuse us?
卡特警探  我们得谈谈
Detective Carter, we need to talk.
晚点聊
I'll catch up with you later.
HR一案现在只剩下些枝节在处理了
So, with HR degraded to the point of irrelevance,
所以我们的工作重心现在转移到西装男身上
my team is shifting priorities back to the man in the suit.
他还逍遥在外  你还想抓到他吧
He's still out there. Do you still want to catch him?
当然
Yes, of course.
好
Good.
我们有些新发现
We have some new information,
知道了他在为谁工作
including who he's working for.
局里一直在追查
Now, the Bureau has been tracking the emergence
私人情报网
of private intelligence networks,
就像中情局和军情六处那种  不过是营利性质的
like the CIA or MI6, but for profit.
我们认为其中最大的一个有中国背景
We think the biggest of these has Chinese backing.
他们有技术  有资源
They've got technology, serious resources,
并一直在招兵买马
and they've been buying up tant.
比如  我们认为马克・斯诺
For instance, we think Mark Snow,
那名联系你的中情局特工
the CIA agent who contacted you,
可能被招募了
may also have been recruited,
可能就是被西装男招募
possibly by the man in the suit.
-真的吗  斯诺  -讲得通
- Really? Snow? - Makes sense.
斯诺被中情局派来追他
I mean, Snow was sent to find this man by the CIA.
他抓到了  然后西装男策反了他
He catches him, and then the man in the suit flips him.
把斯诺招入麾下
Gets Snow to be his asset.
卡特  我想你参与此案
Listen, Carter, I want to read you into this,
但这是机密
but it's classified,
所以上边允许我邀请你
so I've been authorized to offer you
到局里做临时雇员
a temporary assignment to the Bureau.
我知道  凭你的能力
And I know, with your skills,
很快就会升为永久雇员
it'll soon become permanent.
你一加入  我就能让你参与此案
Sooner you're on board, sooner I can fill you in.
所以  请考虑一下
So, please, think about it.
我会的  谢谢你
I will. Thank you.
谢了
Thanks.
卡特
Carter.
你好  警探
Hello, Detective.
我得找到那位朋友
I need to find our friend.
我们有大麻烦了
We have a big problem.
你去城市规划局找他吧
You'll find him at the Department of City Planning.
那她下载完文件就走人了
So she just downloaded the file and walked out?
是的
Yeah.
你们没一个人拦住她
Didn't anyone try to stop her?
当时没人注意啊
Apparently nobody noticed.
我是卡特警探  什么情况
Detective Carter. What do we got?
你也收到报告了吗  警探
You heard the 10-31 too, Detective?
是啊  怎么样了
Yep. So, what is it?
我们刚刚告诉了这位詹宁斯法警
Like we were telling Marshal Jennings here--
詹宁斯法警啊
Marshal Jennings, huh?
经理报告说他的一位职员
The manager called it in 'cause one of his staff,
叫艾比・门罗的姑娘
a girl by the name of Abby Monroe,
非法下载了一份文件
downloaded a file illegally.
两小时前离开了
And walked out with it two hours ago.
等有人发现已经晚了
No one noticed till too late.
有人知道文件里是什么内容吗
Well, does anyone know what's on the file?
我们存了一些重要建筑物的规划
Well, we keep plans here for some important buildings,
不过她拿走的只是
but all she walked out with were some engineering drawings
华尔街附近汉诺威1400的工程样图
for the 1400 block of Hanover near Wall Street.
那里有配电站
It's got an elerical sub-station,
律师事务所  还有家投行总部
lawyers' offices, and the HQ of an investment bank.
没什么关键性基础设施目标
Nothing like a critical infrastructure target.
有没有人知道艾比・门罗住在哪里
So, does anyone know where this Abby Monroe lives?
我们查了
We ran a check.
她给的地址是假的
The address she gave us is fake.
电话号码是投币式公用电话
The phone number is a pay phone.
这里的背景调查可真靠谱
Hey, solid background check there.
怎么说呢
What can I say?
她看起来是个乖巧的孩子
I mean, she seemed like a sweet kid.
居然是装的  真令人失望
Kind of disappointing to find she was a flake.
孩子嘛  说不准的  是吧警探
Kids. You never know. Right, Detective?
是啊
Right.
总之  干得不错  跟进及时
Anyway, good job, following up so quickly.
失陪了各位
Gentlemen.
谢谢你  法警
Thank you, Marshal.
如果有其他发现
Look, if you come up with anything else,
给我电话
give me a call.
约翰  约翰
John. John!
你脑子进水了吗
Are you out of your mind?
居然冒充执法人员
Impersonating a law enforcement officer?
詹宁斯法警  你拿了他的徽章
Marshal Jennings? You took his star?
他反正也不用了
He wasn't using it anymore.
很好用啊  卡特
It's great, Carter.
把徽章一亮  人们就知无不言了
Just flash a badge, and people tell you everything.
你别乱来了  约翰
You gotta stop, John.
唐纳利又来了  一心要抓西装男
Donnelly's back, and he's hot for the man in the suit.
他有了新的想法
He has a new theory.
是啊  我在为中国工作之类的
Yeah, that I'm working for China or something.
我们听到了
We heard.
我们还听到他的邀请了
We also heard his offer.
也许调到联调局对你有好处
Maybe a transfer to the FBI would be good for you.
你们俩监听我的全部谈话吗
Do you listen to all of my conversations?
多多少少吧
More or less.
你气色不错  卡特
You're looking nice, Carter.
看来这位卡尔・比彻对你也有好处
Maybe this Cal Beecher would be good for you too.
他对你好就行了
Long as he treats you right.
他敢惹你生气  我去找他算账
He messes with you, he'll be hearing from me.
好吧  行了  听着
Okay. All right, look.
我们得讨论下界线问题了
We're gonna have to set some boundaries here.
当然
Well, sure.
你和卡尔进展到"某种程度"时
Things get heavy with you and Cal,
我们会闭上眼睛不看
we'll tune out right away.
当我没说
Never mind.
艾比・门罗是怎么回事
What's the deal with Abby Monroe?
我想查查她是不是有麻烦了
I was checking to see she wasn't in trouble.
看来晚了一步
Looks like I'm a bit late.
卡特  你能不能帮我拿到那个摄像头
Carter, can you get me footage from that camera
两小时前的录像
from about two hours ago?
还有那个摄像头
And that camera too?
谢了
Thank you.
这是艾比
There's Abby.
你能否查到
Were you able to trace
那辆摩托车的主人  警探
the owner of the motorcycle, Detective?
不能  因为这辆车是
No, because it was stolen
四天前从皇后区一家二手车展厅被偷走的
from a second-hand showroom in Queens four days ago.
我从抢劫组拿到了监控录像
I got the camera tapes out of the Robbery Squad.
我看到有个单身男子
I see the perp is a single male.
你现在在看录像吗
You looking at the footage now?
是的  怎么了
Yes. Why?
随便问问
No reason.
用炸药引信炸开了锁
Blew the locks with det cord.
没理会警报
Ignored the alarms,
因为他清楚自己能在30秒内脱身
'cause he knew he'd be less than 30 seconds.
他徒手打碎了钥匙柜
He broke the key case with his bare hand.
选好了车
Chose his machine.
令人惊叹
That's impressive.
怎么  怎  怎么回事
What is--what-- what is going on here?
别告诉我你们俩还能看到我的电脑
Don't tell me you can see what's on my computer too.
我是怎么说界限问题来着
What did I say about setting boundaries?
那是假手
That's a prosthetic hand.
高档假体
High-end prosthetic,
用炸药引信进入
use of det cord to gain entry into a building.
依我看  是退役军人
My guess, ex-military.
所以才会跟艾比认识
Might explain his connection to Abby.
问题是  他们在干什么
The question is, what are they doing?
我想答案你不会喜欢
I don't think you're gonna like the answer.
调度站刚刚回应了我的车牌协查要求
Comp stat just flagged my license plate inquiry.
那辆摩托车
The same motorcycle was seen
被交通灯摄像头拍到
on a traffic light camera near a robbery
三天前出现在新泽西一起建筑工地抢劫中
at a construction site in New Jersey three nights ago.
抢走了什么
What was stolen?
爆炸物  塞姆汀塑性炸药
Explosives. Semtex.
足有九公斤  还有爆破雷管
20 pounds of it, and blasting caps.
这样看来  偷爆炸物
Let's see, theft of explosives,
偷华尔街上一栋建筑物的工程平面图
theft of engineering plans for a block on Wall Street.
这家伙可能是下一个蒂莫西・麦克维
This guy could be the next Timothy Mcveigh,
曾在1995年的俄克拉荷马州制造过一起导致168人丧生的爆炸案
而那位姑娘跟他一起
and your girl is working with him.
他也许是拐骗她牵涉其中的
He may have manipulated her into getting involved.
那她也是牵涉其中了
She's still involved.
抱歉  我得履行我的职责
I'm sorry. I'm gonna have to do my job.
我得对她发布全境通告
I'm gonna have to put her name out on an APB.
我们得先找到她
We've got to find her first.
奥尔森  你在55局工作过
Hey, Olson, you worked at the 55.
你认不认识一个叫卡尔・比彻的缉毒警探
You know a narco detective named Cal Beecher?
当然认识
Oh, yeah, sure do.
我们以前都叫他纯金卡尔
We used to call him 18-karat Cal.
衣服好  车子好
Better suits, better cars,
女友好  全都好过我们
better girls than the rest of us.
也许他只是品味好
Maybe he just had better taste.
也许他是受贿
Or maybe he was on the take.
你听我说过吗
Did you hear me say that?
不知道  你说什么了
Don't know. What are you saying?
他曾是卧底缉毒警
Look, he was undercover narcotics.
毒品进进出出  大笔钱来来回回
A lot of buy-and-busts, a lot of money hanging around.
不过  你打听这个干嘛
Anyway, why you want to know?
就是最近老见着他
I just been seeing him around.
是啊  他在和卡特警探约会
Yeah. He's been hanging around Detective Carter.
人家会招蜂引蝶啊  弗斯科
Bees like honey, Fusco.
是啊
Yeah.
我只是说  像艾比这样
I'm just saying, but the way Abby
奋不顾身  舍弃一切
went off the grid, cut all ties,
她肯定计划着什么  芬奇
she's planning something, Finch.
你觉得这位优秀学生想要炸掉华尔街吗
You think our honor student wants to blow up Wall Street?
可能她男朋友想
Well, her boyfriend might.
他可不是第一个走极端的退伍士兵
He isn't the first vet to try something extreme.
我们这种人本来就古怪  芬奇
We are an odd bunch, Finch.
你是挺古怪  里瑟先生  而且你错了
You are odd, Mr. Reese. You're also wrong.
如果艾比牵涉的是境内恐怖主义
If Abby were involved with domestic terrorism,
这属于相关信息
which would be a relevant crime,
机器会把她的号码给到
the machine would have given her number to--
给到现在政府中负责此事之人
to whoever now runs that end of things at the government,
而不会给到我们
not to us.
无论她是威胁的目标  还是威胁的来源
Whether she's the target or the source of the threat,
原因肯定是私人性质的
the issues must be personal.
好吧  那我们还有什么线索  芬奇
Fine, but what leads do we have left, Finch?
有两条
We have two.
第一  她给短期工中介的投币式公用电话号码
First, the pay phone number that she gave the temp agency.
在皇后区的一个街角
It's a street corner in Queens.
中介之前肯定
The agency must have been able
通过那个电话联系过她
to contact her there at one point.
也许可以找到她住所的线索
It might give you a clue as to where she's living.
好  那第二条呢
Okay. And the second lead?
她去年工作的那个地方
The one stable point in her life for the last year--
那个慈善组织  "归国英雄之家"
the charity, Homes For Our Returning Heroes.
我去查这个
I'll check that one out.
好啊  你应该多出门走动
Good. You need to get out more.
你心情可真好  里瑟先生
You're in a good mood, Mr. Reese.
是好
I am.
我早上一觉醒来  感觉
I woke up this morning and felt--
我斟酌再三才能把这话说出来  我感觉很幸福
it took me a while to put my finger on it, but I felt happy.
肯定是因为这份工作
Must be this job.
我很开心
Well, I'm glad.
抱歉  小熊  这次不行
Sorry, Bear. Not now.
艾比接入了这个公用电话
Abby tapped into that pay phone.
维多利亚公寓
日租  周租  月租
我想我找到
I think I've found
这对雌雄大盗之前的藏身之处了
where our Bonnie and Clyde have been laying low.
乔什・门罗  艾比的弟弟
Josh Monroe, Abby's little brother.
我是艾比家的老朋友
I'm an old friend of Abby's family,
我来纽约
and as I was visiting New York,
他们拜托我找找艾比住在哪里
they asked if I'd try to find out where Abby is
为什么要辞职
and why she left her job here.
她没告诉家里吗
She never told them?
抱歉  但我不得不解雇她
Well, I'm sorry, but I had to fire her.
-解雇她  到底为什么呢  -偷东西
- Fire her? What on earth for? - Stealing.
一开始  只是些现金  我就没多追究
At first, it was just petty cash, and I let it go,
以为只是粗心大意  但后来我发现
thinking it was simple carelessness, but then I found
她偷偷潜入我们慈善组织的账户
she was sneaking into the Charity's accounts,
想转钱出去  一大笔钱
trying to move money around-- significant amounts.
查普先生
Mr. Chapple,
这不像我认识的艾比
that really doesn't sound like the Abby I know.
很遗憾  这是事实
Well, unfortunately, it's true.
我们向有经济困难的退伍士兵发放低息贷款
We give low-cost loans to veterans in financial trouble.
有一点点丑闻
Any hint of a scandal,
捐款者就会抽身走人
and our donations would just dry right up.
艾比必须走人
Abby had to go.
妈  爸
Hi, mom. Hi, dad.
要是你们看到这个  就说明我现在有麻烦了
If you're watching this, you'll know I'm in trouble.
你们上次对我发火  还是在我八岁的时候
I don't think you've really been mad at me since I was eight,
那时我把乔什绑在滑板上
that time I tied Josh to his skateboard
把他从山上推下滑到我们家门口
and pushed him down the hill in front of our house
想看他能有多快
to see how fast he would go.
那以后  我一直都很乖  循规蹈矩
Since then, I've always tried to be good, keep the rules.
这次我要干件彻底逆转的大事
Now I'm gonna break them in a big way.
为什么  原因既复杂  也简单
Why? Well, it's complicated and it's simple.
因为我在做正确的事
I'm doing it because it's right,
我知道乔什也会同意的
and I know Josh would agree with me.
他是我弟弟  但我一直敬佩他
He was my little brother, but I always looked up to him,
我知道他会为我骄傲的
and I know that he would be proud of me,
我希望你们了解真相后也会如此
just like I hope you are when you know the truth.
我爱你们  真希望你们不用看到这个
I love you, and I hope you never have to see this.
知道她为什么要偷东西吗
Any idea why she started stealing?
应该是在她认识某个退役的海军陆战队员之后
I believe the trouble started when she met a former marine.
他来公司时他们俩聊过
They'd talk when he came by the offices.
他不知怎么的  反正对艾比影响很大
Somehow, he must have made an impression on Abby,
因为从那以后她就开始偷东西了
'cause, just about that time, she started stealing.
我不明白  陆战队员怎么会来这呢
I don't understand. Why did this marine come here?
不好意思
I'm sorry.
我们与贷款用户签有
We have a strict confidentiality agreement
严格的保密协议
with all of our loan recipients.
简而言之  不是很愉快
Suffice it to say, it was not a pleasant visit.
至少告诉我他叫什么
Could you at least tell me his name?
尚恩・科尔曼下士
Corporal Shayn Coleman,
爆炸物处理专家
explosives ordinance disposal expert.
他的右臂三年前
Lost his right arm
在阿富汗拆除简易爆炸装置时失去了
defusing an IED in Afghanistan three years ago.
他就是偷摩托车的人
He's our motorcycle thief.
我查了尚恩在俄亥俄老家的父母
I tracked down Shayn's parents in his hometown in Ohio.
他们两个多月没见到他了
They haven't seen him in more than two months.
他们知道他有麻烦了吗
Did they know he was in trouble?
他们说他房子的赎回权被取消了
They said he'd had his home foreclosed on,
他未婚妻甩了她
and his fiancee dumped him.
他肯定是为此去找查普的
Must be why he went to Chapple--
希望能再次贷款
to ask for another loan.
不知道发生了什么事  反正是足以
However it happened, this is more than enough
把人推向不归路了
to tip someone over the edge.
他是我们要找的人  我得对他发布全境通告
He's our guy. I'm adding his name to the APB.
做你该做的吧  警探
Do what you have to do, Detective.
芬奇  你还在吗
Finch, are you still there?
是的
Yes.
我看到菲利普・查普在和两个携带武器的人碰面
I'm watching Philip Chapple meet with two armed men.
他们什么样
What are they like?
坦白说  像你  低调而危险
Like you, to be honest-- low-key and vaguely menacing.
我估计他是在告诉他们追踪
I suspect he's telling them to follow me
我身上的GPS发射器信号
via the GPS transponder
我离开时他放进我口袋里的
he slipped into my pocket as I was leaving.
那发射器现在何处呢
And where is the transponder now?
在一辆新泽西牌照的洗衣车上
It's on a laundry van with Jersey plates.
干得漂亮  芬奇
Nice work, Finch.
很明显  查普不会放过追踪艾比的任何机会
Obviously, Chapple will take any opportunity to track Abby down.
她的计划肯定与他有关
What she's planning must connect to him too.
等慈善组织关门后  我再潜进去
When the charity closes, I'll go back in,
看看能发现什么
see what I can find.
我说你该多出门走动
When I said you need to get out more,
可不是这个意思
I didn't mean that.
我去搞定
Let me take care of it.
没有无风险的人生  里瑟先生
No such thing as a risk-free life, Mr. Reese,
艾比是我们的当务之急
and Abby is still our priority.
你在那等她
You wait for her.
我回去
So, I'll go back in,
看看查普究竟在隐藏什么
see what exactly Chapple's hiding.
我进来了
I'm inside,
不过报警装置已经被破坏了
but the alarm has been tampered with.
可能是人家已经在恭候你了  哈罗德
That's because they could be waiting for you, Harold.
怎么了  芬奇  快离开
What was that? Finch, get out now.
你是谁
Who the hell are you?
我是谁并不重要  科尔曼先生
Who I am is not important, Mr. Coleman.
你怎么知道我的名字  你在这做什么
How do you know my name? What are you doing here?
我估计是和你一样
The same thing as you, I expect,
不过你已经惊动了全楼
and since you woke the whole building,
我们得快点了
we better hurry.
我去找你
I'm on my way to you.
拜托  只管离开  芬奇
Please, just walk away now, Finch.
你是谁
Who are you?
放开我
let go of me!
别害怕  我不会伤害你的
It's okay. I'm not gonna hurt you.
芬奇  马上离开
Finch, get out now.
别冒险  我找到艾比了
Don't risk it. I've got Abby.
赶紧离开
Just get out of there.
马上就好  里瑟先生
Nearly done, Mr. Reese.
拜托别这样
Please don't do that.
那就放开我  让我走
Then get off of me. Let me go.
拜托  别动枪
Please, no guns.
芬奇  说话  怎么了
Finch, talk to me. What's happening?
事态有变  里瑟先生
The situation is evolving, Mr. Reese.
他们在那儿
There they go!
站住
Stop right there!
上来  他们会杀了你
Get on, or they'll kill you!
上来
Get on!
芬奇  你没事吧
Finch, are you okay?
除了非法搭乘摩托车外  我还好
Aside from riding on a motorcycle illegally, I'm fine!
保持联系
I'll be in touch!
干得漂亮
Well done.
你好  艾比
Hello, Abby.
我叫约翰
I'm John.
好了  你该离开了
Okay, you should leave now,
我男朋友随时会回来
because my boyfriend's gonna be here any minute.
你男朋友  尚恩
Your boyfriend, Shayn?
我不知道你怎么知道的  不过没错
I don't know how you know that, but yes,
他是陆战队员  你可不会想见他
and he's a marine, so you do not want to meet him.
实际上  我正想见他
Actually, I do want to meet him,
不过一件件来
But first things first.
你留给你父母的视频是什么意思
What does that message to your mom and dad mean?
什么
What?
你闯进我家翻了我的东西
You broke into my room and went through my stuff?
出去  否则我
Get out, or I'm--
怎么  你要报警吗
What? You'll call the police?
我知道建筑设计图和爆炸物的事
I know about the building plans and the explosives.
我就知道  你是查普的人
I knew it. You work for Chapple.
不  不过我很好奇为什么你和尚恩
No, but I'm interested to know why you and Shayn
要追查他
are going after him.
因为查普是个骗子  盗贼
Because Chapple's a liar and a thief,
我不会再多说一句话了
and I'm not saying another word
除非你告诉我你是谁
until you tell me who you are.
我是来阻止你陷入更多麻烦的人
I'm here to stop you from getting into even more trouble.
我问的不是这个
Not what I asked.
你是谁
Who are you?
这有点难回答
I find it hard to answer that,
我自己也说不好
even to myself.
我当过兵  和你弟弟乔什一样
I was a soldier once, like your brother Josh.
不过我很幸运  活着回来了
But I was lucky. I made it out.
-里瑟先生  -在  芬奇  怎么了
- Mr. Reese? - Yes, Finch. What's happening?
我跟尚恩说我们是想帮助他
I've explained to Shayn that we're trying to help him.
他相信你了吗
Did he believe you?
没有  尤其是我告诉他你抓了艾比后
No, especially when I told him that you have Abby.
形势有点紧张
Things are a little tense.
让我跟他说
Let me talk to him.
你是谁
Who is this?
艾比也在问我同样的问题
You know, Abby keeps asking me the same thing.
这真的不重要
It's really not important.
敢伤害她  你会后悔的
If you hurt her, you will be sorry.
你那边也是一样
The same goes for you and my friend.
我们该见见
We should meet.
你跟尚恩离开  我就没法保护你了
Once you leave with Shayn, I can't protect you anymore.
我一开始就没要你保护
I never asked you to protect me in the first place.
不管你在计划什么  我知道原因  艾比
Whatever you're planning, I know why, Abby.
你没能救你弟弟
You couldn't save your brother,
所以想要救尚恩
so you're trying to save Shayn.
我理解  真的
I understand that, truly.
我有切身感受
I'd feel the same way.
告诉我  查普怎么你了
Tell me, what did Chapple do to you?
对我没什么  可他几乎毁了尚恩
Nothing I can't handle, but he nearly destroyed Shayn.
-贷款的事  -对
- By lending him money? - Yes.
查普贷款给他
Chapple made him a loan.
利息一年滚了三倍
The interest rates tripled in a year.
没人能付得起
No one could keep up those payments.
失去房子的人成百上千万
Millions of people lost their homes.
人家也没去偷爆炸物
They don't go around stealing explosives.
尚恩得放手
Shayn should move on.
他失去了房子  失去了未婚妻
He lost his home and his fiancee.
他还曾把自己的朋友介绍给查普
He even introduced some of his buddies to Chapple,
结果其中一个饮弹自尽
one of whom shot himself
就在失去的房子门口
on the porch of the house he no longer owned.
让他这么放手不理吗
Should he move on from that?
我查过查普的文件
Look, I went through Chapple's files.
发现了他的所作所为
I saw what he was doing.
有成百上千
There are hundreds,
成百上千的士兵失去了家园
hundreds of soldiers who lost their homes.
你想要做什么  艾比
What are you gonna do, Abby?
做正确的事
The right thing.
我能走了吗
Can I go now?
我猜你给他放追踪器了吧
I assume you put a tracker on him.
恕我自夸  远不止此
Rather a clever one, if I do say so myself.
他的假肢由肌电感应器控制
His prosthetic arm is controlled by myoelectric sensors
无线连接
by way of a wireless link,
我复制了连接  二次编程
so I cloned the link and reprogrammed it
路过任何手机都会强制配对
to attempt a forced pair with every cell phone they pass.
留下清晰的GPS轨迹
leaving a nice GPS trail.
干得漂亮  芬奇
Well done, Finch.
而且是在狂飚的摩托车后座上完成的
Especially on the back of a speeding motorcycle,
对了  感觉好刺激
which was exhilarating, by the way.
我想自己也弄一辆
I might have to get myself one.
加班啊
Working late?
是啊
Yeah.
总是有事做
It's always something, you know?
是啊  有什么事吗  卡特
Yeah. Is something wrong, Carter?
唐纳利今天邀请我了
Donnelly made me an offer today.
什么  我有情敌了  那家伙吗
What, I got competition? From that guy?
不  不是那种邀请
No, not that sort of offer.
他  邀我加入联调局
He, invited me to join the FBI.
兴许是好事
Could be a good move.
虽说宁为鸡头不为凤尾
I mean, yeah, small fish in a big pond,
不过想想职业前途  卡特  还有收入
but think of the prospects, Carter, and the money.
你应该去
You should do it.
可我的孩子呢
But what about my kid?
我是说  恐怕得
I mean, it--it'll probably mean
从纽约搬走
I have to move out of New York.
你是说我再也见不到你了吗
You mean I'd never see you again?
我是卡尔
It's Cal.
复制手机
卡尔・比彻
强制配对
没问题  不见不散
No problem. I'll see you then.
我们说到哪儿了
Now what were we talking about?
再也见不到我了
About never seeing me again.
对
Right.
比彻  卡尔文
警探  缉毒组
我是卡尔
It's Cal.
获取通话记录
卡尔  我是阿伦佐・奎恩  能见见吗
Cal, Alonzo Quinn. Can we meet?
奎恩  阿伦佐
HR头目
泰瑞尔公园  半小时后吧
Tyrell Park. Say, 30 minutes?
从属关系不明
没问题
No problem.
希望你帮我个忙  卡尔
I'm hoping you can help me out, Cal.
您尽管说  奎恩先生
Any way I can, Mr. Quinn.
市长发现皇冠高地犯罪率暴增
The mayor has seen this crime spike in Crown Heights--
涉毒  抢劫  还有命案
drug busts, burglaries, even homicides.
他想让我查查到底怎么回事
He wants me to find out what's happening.
我告诉他我的教子消息灵通
I told him I got a godson who's got his ear to the ground.
怎么样
So, do you?
皇冠高地  是的
Crown Heights, yeah.
应该是俄罗斯人  彼得・约格洛夫
We think it's a Russian, Peter Yogorov.
曾在布莱顿海滩干  后来被以利亚踢走了
Used to work Brighton Beach till Elias kicked him out.
我们认为他在幕后主使
We believe he's pulling strings from the inside,
想拿下高地那里
working to take over the Heights.
你在干嘛  西蒙斯
What are you doing here, Simmons?
我在监视你  你个老狐狸
I'm keeping an eye on you, you slippery little mutt.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
关你屁事
None of your business.
你在跟踪卡尔・比彻
You're following Cal Beecher.
在帮卡特查他
You're checking him out for Carter?
不  我就是想知道
No, I've been wondering
你还对谁胡说八道了
who else you've been flapping your gums to.
你埋戴维森那事吗
About you burying Davidson?
没对比彻说  目前没
Not Beecher. Not yet.
你越界了  居然给卡特打电话
You crossed a line when you made that call to Carter,
把戴维森被杀引向我
pointing her towards me in the Davidson murder.
越什么界
What line is that?
越"哥我不在乎"这条界
The line where I don't give a crap anymore.
给我小心点
So watch your back.
你知道这种话我听过多少次了吗
You know how many times I've heard that?
可我还在这里  潇洒着呢
And here I am, beautiful as ever.
回家吧  弗斯科
Go home, Fusco.
你来干嘛  西蒙斯
What are you doing here, Simmons?
我说了  回家
I said, go home.
这是手机定位轨迹
There's our cell phone trail.
看来艾比和尚恩
It looks like Abby and Shayn
要去汉诺威1400
are heading for the 1400 block of Hanover.
问题是  哪儿呢
Question is, what's there?
这片所有商户我都列出来了
I've listed every business name on the block,
交叉比对从查普电脑里下载的资料
cross-checking against the download of Chapple's computer.
有了  是家投行  莫顿・瓦特
Bingo. An investment bank, Merton Watts.
也许他在那儿有账户
Maybe he has an account there.
电脑记录上可没有
Not according to his computer records.
-那保险箱呢  -存什么呢
- Then a safe deposit box? - What would he keep in it?
账户显示  查普钱不多
According to his accounts, Chapple's not rich.
艾比说他一堆贷款的赎回权都被取消了
Abby said hundreds of the loans he made were foreclosed on.
没准儿是银行给提成
If he's getting kickbacks from the banks--
有这可能
You may be right.
莫顿・瓦特对查普抵押的房产
Merton Watts has first lien
拥有第一置留权
on any properties Chapple loans money on.
就是说他们可以拍卖所有抵押产业
That means they handle all foreclosure sales.
然后和查普分账
And split the profits with Chapple,
他就存在银行的保管箱里
which he keeps in his safe deposit box at the bank.
也就是艾比和尚恩要找的
That's what Abby and Shayn are after.
她为何要这么做  为了尚恩吗
Why is she doing this? For Shayn?Dialogue: 0,0:26:29.29,0:26:31.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对  还有她弟弟
Yes. And for her brother.
她总觉得亏欠
She still feels a debt.
亡者就是有这种能量  你懂的
The dead have a power like that, as you know.
那他们要怎么做
So, how are they going to do this?
塞姆汀塑性炸药加建筑设计图
Semtex and building plans.
先找个薄弱点
They'll find a soft entry point
轰开缺口进入保险库
and blast their way into the vault.
我喜欢这俩孩子
I like these kids.
我喜欢他们活着
I'd like them to live.
拜托抢在查普雇的凶徒之前找到他们
Please try to get to them before Chapple's thugs do.
系统在备份
System's back up.
他们从保管箱拿走东西了吗
They get anything from the safe?
密码和钥匙
The box code and the keys.
可他们进不去银行的保险库
But there's no way they can get into the vault at the bank,
是吧
is there?
你以为呢
What do you think?
警方都说他们偷了爆炸物
Police band says they stole explosives
还有工程平面图
and engineering plans.
那赶紧去  搞定他们
Well, get down there. Deal with them.
那你得掏钱多雇人了
You have to pay for another man.
那片儿地方太大
It's a big area to cover.
不计成本  必须搞定
Whatever you need. Just finish it.
卡特  你得马上过来
Carter, I need to see you immediately.
能把手机交出来吗
Can I have your phone?
怎么了  唐纳利
What's going on, Donnelly?
抱歉  不过我认为此人所服务的组织
I'm sorry, but I think the organization our man works for
掌握颇多先进科技
has some sophisticated capabilities.
比如窃听警方电话
Like wire-tapping cops?
怎么回事
Has something happened?
我想我们有突破了
I think we got our break.
西装男参与了一桩上东区
The man in the suit was involved in a robbery at a charity
慈善组织抢劫案
on the upper east side.
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
在我告诉你之前  我必须确定
Now, before I can let you in, I have to know
你是否接受局里的临时雇员职位
if you'll accept the temporary assignment to the Bureau.
好  我接受
Okay, yes.
好  你不会后悔的
Good. You won't regret it.
我们追踪此人有十个月了
So, we've been tracking this man for ten months.
每次我们一靠近
Every time we get close,
他都能从我们眼皮底下溜走
he slips right out from under us,
就好像有守护天使一样
as if he has some guardian angel.
之后我就全力搜寻线索  任何线索
All I've looked for since then is a lead, any lead,
后来我意识到了  电话
and then I realized, the phone.
他和他的联络员一直保持着通讯
He's in constant communication with his handlers.
我也想到过
I thought of that.
交叉对比了他所到的犯罪现场周边
Cross-checked crime scenes he was reported at
手机基站日志中的手机串号
with cell tower logs of IMEIs.
-一无所获  -对  一无所获
- Came up with nothing. - Exactly. Nothing.
匡提科的工程师分析了他从下城区
Our engineers at Quantico analyzed the cell tower traffic
溜走那晚的手机基站通信数据
from that night he gave us the slip downtown.
在无线网络和收音机噪音之下
Under the wireless and radio noise,
他们发现了一个有独特标识的
they found short bursts of a cloned IMEI
复制手机串号的短波信号
with a unique signature.
我分配了联调局的机群搜寻该信号
I tasked an FBI computer cluster to search for that signature.
24小时前  机群上线
24 hours ago, the cluster came online.
它发现了另一个复制手机串号的信号
It spotted another burst of cloned IMEIs
与抢劫案的时间地点完全吻合
at the exact time and location of the robbery.
是他
It's him.
我已经让特警队待命了
I've got SWAT teams standing by.
只要他用那个电话  我们就能逮住他
If he uses that phone, we'll have him.
艾比  你做得够多了
Abby, this is far enough.
下面我来吧
I'll handle this from here.
回公寓等我
I'll meet you back at the apartment.
不  要么一起  要么不做
No. No, together or nothing.
你已经冒了太多险  艾比
You've risked enough, Abby.
这不是你的战争
This isn't your fight right now.
这就是我的战争  你就是我的战争
This is my fight. You're my fight.
要我就不会这么做
I wouldn't do that.
或这么做
Or that.
说实话
Now, the truth...
不然我亲手把你们交给警察
or I take you to the cops myself.
我知道你们是来这儿偷查普的钱
I know you're here to steal Chapple's money.
偷完以后呢
What then?
我们想把钱还给被偷的人
We want to give it back to the people he stole it from.
怎么还
How?
我们还没想到那么远
We haven't thought that far ahead.
你们根本就没想远过
You haven't thought very far at all.
为什么不找警察或者律师
Now, why not go to the cops or a lawyer?
艾比找了
Abby did.
她去找地检官  可查普抢先一步
She went to the DA, but Chapple got there first,
打点了那里
spread his poison.
地检甚至威胁要起诉她
The DA even threatened to prosecute her
盗窃和诽谤
for theft and slander.
等我回到公寓
When I got to my apartment,
查普的打手就等在那里
one of Chapple's mercenaries was there.
他打了我
He beat me up.
说我如果我再多说一个字
He said if I said another word,
他会回来用枪打爆我的头
he would come back and put a bullet in my head.
穿过这里就是银行了吧
I assume the bank's through there?
炸了这堵墙  我们就到银行底下了
We blow that wall, we're underneath it.
约翰  这太过分了
John, this has gone far enough.
是吗  芬奇
Has it, Finch?
是的  阻止他们  我来搞定查普
Yes. Stop them. I can deal with Chapple.
查普伤了他们  芬奇
Chapple hurt them, Finch.
他们试过走法律途径  可是没用
They tried the law. The law wasn't interested.
他们还有什么办法呢
What have they got left?
再说了  我向来对那些
Besides, I've always had a thing
坑退伍士兵的人颇有意见
about people who screw with veterans.
约翰  这太冒险了
John, it's far too risky.
你说什么来着  哈罗德
What did you say, Harold?
没有无风险的人生
No such thing as a risk-free life.
动手吧
Let's do it.
等地铁通过
Wait for the subway.
现在
Now.
这就是保险箱的位置
This is where the safe deposit boxes are.
我们意识到无法从银行里面接近它
We realized we couldn't get to them from inside the bank,
所以我们决定让它来接近我们
so we decided to bring them to us.
你们要炸房顶
You're gonna blow the roof.
这儿有情况
We got something here.
约翰  你那边如何
John, what's your situation?
再给我十分钟
Ten more minutes.
我发现了个情况
I'm seeing what I can only describe
我们的电话连线有干扰
as interference on our phone link.
是根吗
Is it Root?
不是  是广谱扫描
No, it's a broad spectrum sweep,
出自重型计算机
heavy-duty computer power.
根要精致得多
Root's more subtle than that.
一定是联调局的朋友
It must be our FBI friend.
马上下线  立刻出来
Stay off the line and please get out now.
如果尚恩和艾比不出来  抛下他们
If Shayn and Abby won't come, leave them.
我不抛下别人
I don't leave people,
他们在打击坏蛋
and they're bringing down a very bad man.
你的实验不就是为这个吗
Now, isn't that what your experiment's all about?
我的实验是为了救人命
My experiment is about stopping people from getting killed,
不是为了抢银行
not robbing banks.
五分钟后我们就出来
Five minutes and we're out.
三  二  一
In three, two, one.
走
Let's go.
这里  158
There, 158.
他的账户开在委内瑞拉的银行
His account's in a bank in Venezuela.
-这就是是你们要找的吗  -一直都是
- Is this what you need? - Is it ever.
这里有三千多万美金
There's more than $30 million here.
他的慈善组织偷了三千万美金
His charity stole $30 million.
走吧  原路返回
Then let's go, back the way we came.
趴下
Get down!
-你还好吗  -现世报啊
- You okay? - Karma at last.
这些凶徒都是查普雇的  是吧
It's those thugs Chapple hired, isn't it?
银行还有三十分钟开门
The bank opens in 30 minutes.
我们必须在那之前离开
We've got to get out before then.
撑住
Hang tight.
911来电
911 call.
华尔街附近地下疑似爆炸
Possible underground explosion near Wall Street.
我们在同样的区域追踪到了手机串号信号  是他
We're tracking IMEI bursts in the same area. It's him.
我们召了特警队来
Now, we hook up a SWAT en route.
-你来吗  -当然
- Are you with us? - Yeah, of course.
我打完电话就去
I just need to make a phone call.
好  快点
All right, make it quick.
妈  你能送泰勒去学校吗
Hi, mom, can you make sure Taylor gets to school?
妈  你喝酒了  卡特
Mom? You been drinking, Carter?
告诉哈罗德  唐纳利正要前往华尔街
Tell Harold, Donnelly is headed to Wall Street.
他说约翰在那儿  他在跟踪电话
He says John is there. He's tracking the phones.
好的  妈  多谢  我爱你
Okay, mom. Yes. Thank you. I love you.
我是弗斯科
Hey, it's Fusco.
你家神奇小子在哪儿都好  最好不在华尔街
Wherever Wonder Boy is, I hope it's not near Wall Street,
因为唐纳利正要过去
because that's where Donnelly's heading.
约翰就在那里
That's exactly where John is.
莫顿・瓦特投资银行  汉诺威大街
Merton Watts Investment Bank, Hanover Street.
卡特还说了什么
Yeah, plus Carter said something
你们的手机问题
about him being up on your phones.
果然如我所虑
Just as I feared.
尽量帮我们在银行制造干扰
Anything you can do to run interference for us at the bank,
警探  我感激不尽
Detective, I would be most grateful.
我想你认识这位先生
I take it you know this gentleman?
彼得・约格洛夫  俄罗斯黑帮的执刑人
Peter Yogorov, enforcer for the Russian mob.
至少以利亚除掉他老爹之前是
Least he used to be until Elias took out his old man.
这点可能对我们有利
Seems like something that might be to our advantage.
反击以利亚吗
To hit back at Elias?
组建另一个收入来源
To build another revenue stream.
约格洛夫现在
Yogorov's at MCC,
正和他弟弟拉兹罗一起候审
awaiting trial with his little brother Lazlo.
地检官死死咬住他一堆罪名
DA's got him dead to rights on a dozen different counts.
这方面我们可以插手
Maybe we can do something about that.
需要搞地检官吗
You need something on the district attorney?
我来处理
Let me handle that.
给我们的使者以斯巴达式回应
By going all Spartan on our emissaries,
以利亚表达得很清楚了  关系完蛋了
Elias has made it clear-- that relationship is over.
我们要交些新朋友
We need new friends.
你要我去跟俄罗斯人谈判
You want me to talk to the Russians?
公开谈判
Open negotiations?
他们有条件  但如果和我们合作
They have all the right pieces, but with us behind them,
现金流不会再是问题
cash flow would no longer be an issue.
了解  老大
Understood, boss.
刚刚听到个有趣的事
Just heard something interesting.
看起来我们的眼中钉唐纳利
Looks like that pain-in-the-ass Donnelly
就快追上西装男了
finally caught up with the man in the suit.
还不到早上七点  今天已如此美妙
Not even 7:00am, and already a perfect day.
银行就要开始营业了  约翰
The bank's about to open, John.
你在哪里
Where are you?
里瑟先生  发生什么事了
Mr. Reese, what's happening?
我讨厌这么说  芬奇
I hate to say this, Finch,
但是我们有点麻烦了
but we're in a bit of a pickle here.
上楼去大厅
Get upstairs to the foyer.
我给你们全都准备了身份证和通行证
I have IDs and passes for all of you.
掩护我们
Cover us.
你在找什么
What are you looking for?
衣服
Clothes.
你们需要换装
You need to get changed.
我们得打扮成银行职员的样子
We're gonna dress up like bankers.
我们要爬上去
We're gonna climb up there
直接从正门出去
and walk right out the front door.
来吧
Come on.
总部刚刚捕获到一次目标信号
Base just picked up another burst of comms from the target.
-同样位置  -是  长官
- Same location? - Yes, Sir.
你能追踪到他  但是听不到声音
So, you can track him, but you can't hear what he's saying?
知道他在跟谁谈话吗
Do you know who he's talking to?
暂时不知道
Not yet.
把枪给我  你带艾比走
Give me the gun. You take Abby.
你做得够多了
You've done enough.
是我害我们陷入了困境
I'm the one who got us into this mess.
是我们一起害自己陷入了困境
We all got ourselves into this mess.
我们得一起救出自己
We're all going to get ourselves out.
你们上到大厅后  找哈罗德
Now, when you get up to the foyer, look for Harold.
我随后就来
I'll be right behind you.
现在
Now.
看来里面没事
Looks like nothing's going on inside.
不  信号仍在活动  911报警电话称
No, the signal's still active, and the 911 call said
爆炸发生在地下  记得吗
the explosion was underground, remember?
他在里面
He's in there.
一队跟我从前面进去
All right, one team in front with me,
二队  绕到后面
second team, around the back.
半小时内行动
We move in 30.
借过  女士
Excuse me, ma'am.
我是银行的客户
I'm a client here at the bank.
我想现在进入地下室
I need to get into the vault now.
你们好  拿着
Hello. Here. Take these.
我叫哈罗德・冉  开了一家保险公司
My name is Harold Wren. I own an insurance company.
你们是我的同事  我们在这里有预约
You are my associates. We have an appointment here.
约翰呢
Where's John?
联调局  所有人背靠墙上
FBI! Everybody back against the wall!
-待在原地  -不要动
- Stay where you are! - Don't move!
-举起手来  -手伸出来
- Hands up! - See your hands!
大厅安检
Foyer's secure.
检查身份证  统统不许离开
Check every ID. No one leaves.
一半人留下  一半跟我走
Half your men here, half with me.
是  长官
Yes, Sir.
-我们走  -手举起来  伸出来
- Let's go! - Hands where we can see them!
你  不要动
You! Don't move!
-请出示您的身份证  -约翰  能听到吗
- See your ID, please? - John, can you hear me?
尚恩和艾比都安全了
Shayn and Abby are safe.
联调局的到银行了  快走
FBI are in the bank. Get out now.
这边有人来了
We got company.
扔掉武器  快给我出来
Lose the weapons and get the hell out.
约翰  能听到吗  你得马上走
John, can you hear me? You must get out now.
A  这里是D  地下室安全
Alpha, this is Delta. Vault level is secure.
我出不去了  哈罗德
I'm not gonna make it, Harold.
抱歉我搞砸了
Sorry I screwed up.
我昨天说的是真心话
But I meant what I said yesterday.
谢谢  哈罗德  很好玩
So, thanks, Harold. It was fun.
约翰
John?
身份证
ID?
哈罗德・冉  环球人寿保险
Harold Wren, Universal Heritage Insurance.
我的同事
My associates.
你们来银行干嘛
Why are you in the bank?
我们和策略副总裁有个会议
We have a meeting with the vice president of corporate strategy.
身份证
ID.
拿到想要的了吗
Did you get what you wanted?
查普偷的所有钱
All the money Chapple stole.
超过三千万
More than $30 million.
你能利用这些账目做些什么吗
Can you do anything with the accounts?
能
Yes.
我会清空它们  把所有钱都
I'll empty them, deposit every last cent
转到知名的军人慈善组织账户下
into the accounts of reputable military charities.
可以吗
Would that do?
我要送你们俩离开这里
Then I have to get you out of here
离开本州
and out of this state.
只要我们在一起就行
As long as we're together.
检查上层
Check the top level.
检查下面
Check down back.
别担心  我掩护你们
Don't worry. I got you covered.
那约翰呢
What about John?
? It's just a shot away ?
? Baby ?
终于抓到你了
We finally got you.
? It's just a shot away ?
长官  有点问题
Sir, there's a probl.
退后
Step back.
? It's just a shot away ?
? Yeah, yeah, yeah ?
你能认出来吗
Well, do you recognize him?
不能
No.
? Gimme, gimme shelter ?
全拷上
Cuff 'em all.
? Or I'm gonna fade away ?
? War, children ?
? It's just a shot away ?